Josiah Brown

2901 Bledsoe St, Apt 1154 · Fort Worth, TX. 76107

Portfolio: josiahbrown.com (682) 239-6862 · josiah.webdev@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

Passionate React Developer with a strong foundation in software engineering and experience in a diverse range of cultures. Analytical mind with the ability to solve complex problems. Proven leader with project background in web applications, REST APIs, and custom software solutions. Excellent foundation in math and logic with a track record of consistently meeting project deadlines under challenging and fast-paced environments.

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Java, Swift, C++, Assembly, Verilog
Frameworks/Skills: Git/GitHub, React, MongoDB, Redux, REST APIs, Express, Node, Jest, Tailwind, SQL, Figma, Material UI, Heroku, Netlify, SEO, Formik, P5.js, Ajax, React Router, WordPress, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

BAYLOR UNIVERSITY- Waco, TX

May 2021

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

• GPA 3.95

Minor: Mathematics

EXPERIENCE

PANTHER CITY LEATHER – Fort Worth, TX

Jun 2022 – Aug 2022

panthercityleather.com

Full Stack Developer

- Designed and implemented 10 responsive pages and over 20 reusable React components
- Integrated with a Commerce.js/Stripe backend capable of processing payments in 47 countries
- Added cross-browser support and tested on 4 primary browsers (Chrome, Safari, Firefox, Edge)

FREE BURMA RANGERS - Chiang Mai, Thailand

Jun 2021 - May 2022

Volunteer Staff

- Constructed custom software solutions to increase efficiency on the team including a certificate generator used to automatically create diplomas for over 200 students
- Installed 2 off-grid solar power systems capable of outputting ~27kW
- Piloted DJI 4 drone in conflict area to obtain recon info on at least 4 occasions

QORVO - Richardson, TX

May 2020 - Aug 2020

Product Quality Engineering Intern

- Analyzed data and technical documents to obtain a list of over 30 parts to convert to new epoxy
- Overhauled product management system for over 500 parts with end user experience in mind

BROWN WOODWORKING – Fort Worth, TX

May 2015 - Aug 2019

Small Business Owner

- Crafted original woodworking products such as fountain pens, 14' bookcases, and dining tables
- Sold hundreds of custom items to clients and maintained a perfect average 5-star review

ADDITIONAL

- Experience with Scrum/Agile team
- Conversational Thai, vast cultural experience having lived in 3 countries and visited 12